LOUISE FATTON

DEVELOPER



CONTACT

6

0041.78.778.70.38



louise.fatton@hotmail.fr



https://lfatton.github.io/



Fahys 7, 2000 Neuchâtel, Switzerland

EDUCATION

42 CURSUS

Computer Science 42 Paris 2018 — 2022

ERASMUS

English Language and Literature University of Leeds 2014 — 2015

BACHELOR OF ARTS

English Language and Literature & Japanese studies University of Geneva 2012 — 2016

SKILLS

| Technical

C / C# / C++ / Python3

MVC ASP.Net / SQL Server

HTML5 / Less / JavaScript / JQuery

Godot / OpenGL / PixiJS / Vue3

Git / CMake / Makefile / Unix

SUMMARY

Fast learning and passionate software developer with 3 years of experience working in an IT company, I also have taken part on several graphical and game projects during my studies and free time. I mainly worked with small teams for non-working projects, thus gaining experience in various areas of development ranging from programing a raycasting engine to working on gameplays and HUDs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

UDITIS S.A. | 2019 — 2022

Uditis is a 23-year-old company specialising in digital technology based in Peseux, Neuchâtel. It offers web-based solutions and applications as well as IT support. Uditis joined Sequotech Group at the start of 2022 and currently has 65 employees.

- Started as an intern for 6 months, mainly helping improve their inhouse CMS and working solo on a projects management solution from scratch, before being offered a permanent position as a developer.
- Worked on several different projects of varying team size, ranging from 1 to 10 people.
- Last worked on 2 different projects in MVC ASP.Net, while also being part of a team that was dedicated to the CSEM (Swiss Center for Electronics and Microtechnology); maintaining their intranet, and developing new applications curtailed to their needs.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Absinthe&Basilic Restaurant | 2019

Absinthe&Basilic was a restaurant based in Fleurier, Neuchâtel. It unfortunately closed after the first COVID-19 lockdown.

• Migrated their website on WordPress and incorporated the new design.

PASSENGER SERVICE AGENT

Swissport International AG | 2015 — 2016

Swissport is one of the leading companies providing ground services to in airports.

- Student job during my last year at the University of Geneva.
- Part of the section dedicated only to the low-cost airline EasyJet and worked first at the check-in during charter season, before moving on to working at the gates as well.
- Mostly worked on the early shifts (from 4AM to 12.30PM) as I did not mind the change in rhythm and the morning team was really nice.

LOUISE

DEVELOPER

SKILLS

| Spoken languages

French - Mother tongue

English – Fluent

Japanese, German - Basic knowledge

HOBBIES

My first games

Pokémon Gold

Wario Land: Super Mario Land 3

Currently playing

Hades

Eastwards

Spent a lot of time on

Skyrim

The Witcher 3

Zelda: Breath of the Wild

The Sims 4

Fun with friends

Battleblock Theater

Animal Crossing: New Horizons

Overcooked 2

Obsessed with

Stardew Valley ♥

Don't Starve

Horizon Games

Assassin's Creed Black Flag

When not playing

Pole dancing

Reading and cooking

MOST RELEVANT PROJECTS

SCOP

42 Project | 2023

A 3D modelisation project in OpenGL4.6 and C++17. It is a small program loading and displaying a wavefront .obj.

• I did it mostly alone and it helped me get a good grasp on shaders, OpenGL and the maths (especially matrices) behind 3D modeling.

DOOM-NUKEM

42 Project | 2019

The goal was to create a game engine in C based on a mix of Doom and Quake (Duke Nukem) engines using raycasting. We had to make a map editor and a map to binary file compressor as well.

 Including my working career, this is the biggest and more complex project I have worked on, it took us approximately 6 months with a team of 4 people to make.

CROQUETTES NOT INCLUDED

UPsi Jam | 2022

A small management game made with Godot Engine and GDScript. The goal is to herd your cats (more appear as time passes) in a room to take their picture.

- Made in 42 hours with a team of 3 on the given theme 'always more'.
- Quite challenging as we had no game artists and Godot was new to us.

TROMBI

Epic Game Jam | 2021

Bullet hell game made using JavaScript and PixiJS. You play a tie, with a pattern taken from your webcam, trying to survive the working world.

• Made in 2 days with a team of 6 on the given theme 'corporate'.

SYSYPHUS

Epic Game Jam | 2019

First game jam. Rhythmic rogue like game where you play a bird moving a moon up a mountain, developed in JavaScript and PixiJS.

• Made in 2 days with a team of 5 on the given theme 'death'.

EXTRA

ONE OF THE FOUNDING MEMBERS OF AU BÛCHER

An intersectional feminist collective created at the end of 2021. Since then, the collective has been part of various feminist events during the last two years and even organised a one-day festival for women and queer people in May 2022.